Mss.530.1.Ar2.5
American Philosophical Society
American Physical Society and APS. Joint Committee on the History of Theoretical Physics in the Twentieth Century. Collection
Undated
Mss.530.1.Ar2.5
American Philosophical Society
12.5 Linear feet
Primary source materials for the history of quantum physics in the twentieth century, collected under the auspices of the APS and the American Physical Society, with a grant from the National Science Foundation. There are transcripts of the oral history interviews, as well as the working papers of the Committee. These include correspondence with famous figures in physics, with some memoirs, photographs, lectures, etc. On microfilm (see Mss. 530.1 Ar2 ) are manuscripts of Niels Henrick David Bohr and his scientific correspondence (62 reels from the Niels Bohr Archives, Universitets Institut for Teoretisk Fysik, Copenhagen). This collection is described and analyzed in Sources for the History of Quantum Physics: An Inventory and Report, by Thomas S. Kuhn, John L. Heilbron, Paul Forman, and Lini Allen (Philadelphia, 1967). The subject guide derived from the work has subsequently been digitized in its entirety and is available through the finding aid for Mss. 530.1 Ar2.
12.5 linear feet.
American Physical Society and American Philosophical Society. -- Joint Committee on the History of Theoretical Physics in the Twentieth Century.
Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962
Box 1-25
Alternate formats available
Film 1419 (11 reels).
Correspondence.; Lectures.; Oral histories; Photographs; Quantum physics--History
- I. Transcripts of Oral History Recordings, with biographical information
  Scope and Contents note
  In addition to written transcripts of the oral history interviews undertaken during the project, this series also includes correspondence and biographical information.
  Please note: Folders without a scope and content note consist solely of biographical materials.
  - Allard, Georges, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes 14-page transcript of interview which took place in Paris on 10 January 1963.
    Related Archival Materials note
    Audio of interview available for listening (See Mss.530.1.Ar2, Oral History Interviews).
  - Amaldi, Edoardo, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes 34-page transcript of interview which took place in Rome on 8 April 1963.
  - Anderson, Carl David, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Andrade, Edward Neville da Costa, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes 7-page transcript of interview which took place in London on 18 December 1962.
  - Auger, Pierre Victor, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Back, Ernst, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Bargmann, Valentine, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Barkla, C. G., 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Bauer, Edmond H., 1962-1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 1)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Paris on: 8 January 1963 (15 pages) and 14 January 1963 (8 pages).
    Audio of interviews available for listening (See Mss.530.1.Ar2, Oral History Interviews).
  - Bechert, Karl, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Beck, Guido, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Bethe, Hans A., 1961-1964; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes 22-page transcript of interview which took place at Berkeley on 17 January 1964.
  - Birge, R. T., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Bjerrum, Niels, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Blackett, P. M. S., 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes 4-page transcript of unrecorded interview which took place in London on 17 December 1962.
  - Bloch, Felix, 1964; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes 40-page transcript of interview which took place in Palo Alto, California on 14 May 1964.
  - de Boer, Jan, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Bohr, Niels, 1961-1962; 6.0 Item(s) 6 folders (Box 1)
    Includes transcripts of several interviews which took place in Copenhagen on: 31 October 1962 (12 pages); 1 November 1962 (19 pages); 7 November 1962 (15 pages); 14 November 1962 (11 pages); 17 November 1962 (10 pages).
  - Bohr, Fru Niels [Margrethe Norlund Bohr], 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Copnehagen on: 23 January 1963 (17 pages) and 30 January 1963 (20 pages).
  - Boltzmann, Ludwig, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Borelius, Gudmund, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Born, Max, 1960-1962; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 2)
    Includes transcripts of interviews: unknown location, June 1960 (12 pages); Bad Pyrmont, Germany, 17 October 1962 (30 pages); Bad Pyrmont, Germany, 18 October 1962 (21 pages).
  - Bose, Satyendranath, 1961; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Bothe, Walther, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Bragg, William Henry, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Bragg, William Lawrence, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Breit, Gregory, 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Brillouin, Leon N., 1962; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 2)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in New York City on: 29 March 1962 (14 pages); 3 April 1962 (10 pages).
  - de Broglie, Louis, 1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 2)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Paris on: 7 January 1963 (13 pages) and 14 January 1963 (11 pages).
  - de Broglie, Maurice, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Burger, Herman C., 1962; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 2)
    Includes transcripts of two interviews which took place in Utrecht on 15 November 1962 (31 pages).
  - Burgers, Johannes M., 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 2)
    Includes 18-page transcript of interview which took place in Cambridge, Massachusetts on 9 June 1962.
  - Casimir, Henrik B., 1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 2)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Copenhagen on: 5 July 1963 (22 pages) and 6 July 1963 (21 pages).
  - Catalan, Miguel A., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Chadwick, James, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Cockcroft, John D., 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 2)
    Includes 16-page transcript of interview which took place in Cambridge, England on 2 May 1963.
  - Compton, Arthur H., 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Compton, Karl T., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Condon, Edward U., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Coster, Dirk, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Coulson, C. A., 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (Box 2)
    Letter to Thomas Kuhn.
  - Courant, Richard, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 2)
    Includes 16-page transcript of interview which took place in New York City on 9 May 1962.
  - Cunningham, Ebenezer, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 2)
    Includes 15-page transcript of interview which took place in Cambridge, England on 19 June 1963.
  - Curie, Marie, 1961; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Curie, Pierre, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Darrow, Karl Kelchner, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Darwin, Charles Galton, 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Davisson, Clinton Joseph, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Debye, Peter J. W., 1962-1963; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 3)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in New York City on: 3 May 1962 (two sessions, 43 pages) and 4 May 1962 (22 pages).
  - Dee, P. I., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Delbrück, Max, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (Box 3)
  - Dennison, David M., 1964; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 3)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Ann Arbor, Michigan on: 27 January 1964 (12 pages); 28 January 1964 (26 pages); and 30 January 1964 (26 pages).
  - Dieke, Gerhard Heinrich, 1961; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Dirac, P. A. M., 1962-1963; 6.0 Item(s) 6 folders (Box 3)
    Includes transcripts of interviews: Princeton, New Jersey, 1 April 1962 (15 pages); Cambridge, England, 6 May 1963 (18 pages); Cambridge, England, 7 May 1963 (22 pages); Cambridge, England, 10 May 1963 (28 pages); Cambridge, England, 14 May 1963 (32 pages).
  - de Donder, Theophile E., 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Dorgelo, Hendrik B., 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Drude, Paul, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Duane, William, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Eckart, Carl, 1962-1969; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 3)
    Includes 16-page transcript of interview which took place in La Jolla, California on 31 May 1962.
  - Edelstein, Ludwig, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 3)
    Includes 2-page transcript of interview which took place in New York City on 7 May 1962.
  - Ehrenfest, Paul T., 1960; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Ehrenfest-Afanassjewa, Tatiana, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1955-1961; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 3)
    Includes "Relativity Seminar by A. Einstein," a lecture given by Einstein in 1954. Notes of the lecture were taken by J. A. Wheeler, and it was later edited by A. M. Jaffe in 1961. Also includes transcript of "A Talk with Einstein" by Esther Salaman, 1955.
  - Ellis, Charles Drummond, 1961-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Elsasser, Walter M., 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 3)
    Includes 8-page transcript of interview which took place in La Jolla, California on 29 May 1962.
  - Enskog, David, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Epstein, Paul S., 1962; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 3)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Pasadena, California: 25 May 1962 (15 pages); 25-26 May 1962 (12 pages); 2 June 1962 (6 pages).
  - Estermann, Immanuel, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 3)
    Includes 24-page transcript of interview which took place in London on 13 December 1962.
  - Ewald, Peter Paul, 1961-1962; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 3)
    Includes transcripts of interviews: New York City, 29 March 1962 (12 pages); New Milford, Connecticut, 8 May 1962 (22 pages).
  - Fajans, Kasimir, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Feather, Norman, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Fermi, Enrico, 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
    Consists of extensive biographical notes and a finding aid to the Enrico Fermi Papers at the University of Chicago.
  - Fierz, Markus Eduard, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Fock, Vladimir, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Fokker, Adriaan D., 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 4)
    Includes 22-page transcript of interview which took place in Beekbergen, Netherlands on 1 April 1963.
  - Foster, John Stuart, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Fowler, Alfred, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Fowler, Ralph Howard, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Franck, James, 1962-1964; 7.0 Item(s) 7 folders (Box 4)
    Includes transcripts of interviews with Hertha Sponer Franck which took place in Falmouth, Massachusetts on: 9 July 1962 (17 pages); 10 July 1962 (14 pages); 11 July 1962 (21 pages); 12 July 1962 (23 pages); 13 July 1962 (22 pages); and 14 July 1962 (18 pages).
  - Frank, Philipp, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 4)
    Includes 16-page transcript of interview which took place in Cambridge, Massachusetts on 16 July 1962.
  - Frenkel, J. I., 1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Friedrich, Walter, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 4)
    Includes 13-page transcript of interview which took place in Berlin on 15 May 1963.
  - Frisch, Otto R., 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 4)
    Includes 12-page transcript of interview which took place in Cambridge, England on 8 May 1963.
  - Fues, Erwin R., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Furry, Wendell Hinkle, 1960; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Gamow, George, 1946-1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Geiger, Hans, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - George, André, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Gerlach, Walther, 1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 4)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Munich on: 18 February 1963 (34 pages) and 23 February 1963 (22 pages).
  - Germer, Lester Halbert, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Gordon, Walter, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Gorter, Cornelius J., 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 4)
    Includes 29-page transcript of interview which took place in Leiden on 13 November 1962.
  - Goudsmit, Samuel Abraham, 1963; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 4)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in New York City on: 5 December 1963 (30 pages) and 7 December 1963 (two sessions, 51 pages).
  - Grotrian, Walter R. W., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Guth, Eugen, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Haas, Arthur, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Haas, Wander Johannes de, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Hahn, Otto, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Halpern, Otto, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Harteck, Paul, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Hartree, Douglas R., 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Hartree, Mrs. Douglas R., 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 5)
    Includes 3-page transcript of unrecorded interview which took place in Cambridge, England on 12 March 1963.
  - Heisenberg, Werner, 1921-1963; 14.0 Item(s) 14 folders (Box 5)
    Includes transcripts of interviews: Munich, 10 sessions, 30 November 1962-28 February 1963 (259 pages total); Copenhagen, 2 sessions, 5 July 1963-12 July 1963 (41 pages total).
    Also includes copies of letters written by Heisenberg, 1921-1927.
  - Heitler, Walter, 1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 5)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Zurich on: 18 March 1963 (22 pages) and 19 March 1963 (11 pages).
  - Hertz, Gustav L., 1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 5)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Berlin on: 14 May 1963 (32 pages) and 15 May 1963 (8 pages).
  - Herzberg, Gerhard, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Herzfeld, Karl, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 5)
    Includes 16-page transcript of interview which took place in Washington, D.C. on 14 June 1962.
  - Hevesy, Georg von, 1962-1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 5)
    Includes transcripts of interviews: Lafayette, California, 25 May 1962 (19 pages); Stockholm, Sweden, 4 February 1963 (14 pages).
  - Hilbert, David, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Hildebrand, Joel, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 6)
    Includes 13-page transcript of interview which took place at Berkeley on 6 August 1962.
  - Honl, Helmut, 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Holst, Gilles, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Houston, William Vermillion, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Houtermans, F. G., 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (Box 6)
  - Hoyt, Frank Clark, 1964; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 6)
    Includes 24-page transcript of interview which took place in Palo Alto, California on 28 April 1964.
  - Hund, Friedrich, 1962-1963; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 6)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Göttingen on: 25 July 1963 (two sessions, 33 pages) and 26 July 1963 (37 pages).
  - Hylleraas, Egil A., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Infeld, Leopold, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Jauncey, George Eric Macdonald, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Jeans, James Hopwood, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Jensen, Johannes Hans Daniel, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Joffe, Abram, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Joliot, Jean Frederic, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Joos, Georg, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Jordan, Pascual, 1962-1963; 6.0 Item(s) 6 folders (Box 6)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Hamburg on: 17 June 1963 (30 pages); 18 June 1963 (23 pages); 19 June 1963 (27 pages); and 20 June 1963 (21 pages).
  - Kamerlingh Onnes, Heike, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Kapitsa, P. L., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Karman, Theodore von, 1962-1964; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 6)
    Includes 9-page transcript of interview which took place in Pasadena, California on 29 June 1962.
  - Kaufmann, Walter, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Keesom, Walter Hendrik, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Kemble, Edwin C., 1962-1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 6)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Cambridge, Massachusetts on: 11 May 1962 (14 pages); 1-2 October 1963 (two sessions, 19 pages).
  - Kennard, Earle H., 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Klein, Christian Felix, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Klein, Oskar, 1962-1963; 7.0 Item(s) 7 folders (Box 6)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Copenhagen on: 25 September 1962 (12 pages); 20 February 1963 (25 pages); 25 February 1963 (27 pages); 28 February 1963 (21 pages); 15 July 1963 (25 pages); 16 July 1963 (28 pages).
  - Kohn, Hedwig, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 3-page transcript of unrecorded interview which took place in Raleigh, North Carolina on 7 June 1962.
  - Kopfermann, Hans, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Kossel, Walther, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Kronig, Ralph, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 25-page transcript of interview which took place in Delft on 12 November 1962.
  - Kuhn, Heinrich Gerhard, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 7-page transcript of interview which took place in Oxford on 3 May 1963.
  - Kuhn, Werner, 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Kulenkampff, Helmut, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Ladenburg, Rudolf Walter, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lanczos, Cornelius, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Landau, L. D., 1961; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Landé, Alfred, 1962; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 7)
    Includes transcripts of interviews: Berkeley, 4 sessions, 5 March 1962-8 March 1962 (40 pages); Columbus, Ohio, 14 June 1962 (4 pages).
  - Langevin, Jean, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 15-page transcript of interview which took place in Paris on 11 January 1963.
  - Langevin, Paul, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Laporte, Otto, 1964; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 7)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Ann Arbor, Michigan on: 29 January 1964 (27 pages) and 31 January 1964 (31 pages).
  - Lau, Ernst Gustav, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 7-page transcript of interview which took place in Berlin on 15 May 1963.
  - Laue, Max von, 1960-1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lenard, Philipp, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lenzen, Victor F., 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 1-page transcript of unrecorded interview which took place at Berkeley on 28 June 1962.
  - Lewis, Gilbert Newton, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lindemann, Frederick Alexander [Viscount Cherwell], 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lindsay, Robert Bruce, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Loeb, Leonard B., 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 22-page transcript of interview which took place in Pacific Grove, California on 7 August 1962.
  - London, Fritz, 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lorentz, H. A., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lo Surdo, Antonio, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lucas, Rene, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 13-page transcript of interview which took place in Paris on 10 January 1963.
  - Lummer, Otto, 1928, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lunn, Arthur C., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Lyman, Theodore, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Madelung, Erwin, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Majorana, Ettore, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Massey, Harrie Stewart Wilson, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Mayer, Maria Goeppert, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 9-page transcript of interview which took place in La Jolla, California on 20 February 1962.
  - Meissner, Walther, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 11-page transcript of interview which took place in Munich on 8 February 1963.
  - Meitner, Lise, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 21-page transcript of interview which took place in Cambridge, England on 12 May 1963.
  - Michelson, Albert A., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
  - Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Minkowski, Hermann, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
  - Minkowski, Rudolf, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 8)
    Includes 19-page transcript of interview which took place at Berkeley in April 1962.
  - Møller, Christian, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 8)
    Includes 22-page transcript of interview which took place in Copenhagen on 29 July 1963.
  - Morse, Philip McCord, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
  - Moseley, H. G. J., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
  - Mott, Nevill Francis, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 8)
    Includes 16-page transcript of interview which took place in Cambridge, England on 13 May 1963.
  - Mulliken, Robert Sanderson, 1964; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 8)
    Includes 43 pages of transcripts of two interviews which took place in Chicago, Illinois on 1 February 1964.
  - Nernst, Walther, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Nicholson, John William, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Nordheim, Lothar, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 8)
    Includes 23-page transcript of interview which took place in San Diego, California on 30 July 1962.
  - Occhialini, Giuseppe, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Oliphant, Marcus Laurence Elwin, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1926-1966; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 8)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Princeton, New Jersey on 18 November 1963 (21 pages) and 20 November 1963 (32 pages):
    Also includes copies of correspondence, 1926-1935.
  - Ornstein, L. S., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
  - Orowan, Egon, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Paschen, Friedrich, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Pauli, Wolfgang, 1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Pauling, Linus, 1964; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 8)
    Includes transcripts of two interviews which took place in Pasadena, California on 27 March 1964 (67 pages total).
  - Peierls, Rudolf Ernst, 1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 8)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Birmingham on: 17 June 1963 (40 pages) and 18 June 1963 (11 pages).
  - Perrin, Francis, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 8)
    Includes 8-page transcript of interview which took place in Paris on 12 January 1963.
  - Persico, Enrico, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Pettersson, Hans, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (Box 8)
  - Pihl, Mogens, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Planck, Max, 1949-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Podolsky, Boris, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Pohl, Robert Wichard, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 9)
    Includes 19-page transcript of interview which took place in Göttingen on 25 June 1963.
  - Poincare, Henri, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Polanyi, Michael, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 9)
    Includes 13-page transcript of interview which took place at Berkeley on 15 February 1962.
  - Pontecorvo, Bruno, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Pringsheim, Ernst, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Pringsheim, Peter, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Rabi, I. I., 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 9)
    Includes 38-page transcript of interview which took place in New York City on 8 December 1963.
  - Raman, Chandrasekhara Venkata, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ramsauer, Carl, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Ramsay, William, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Rasetti, Franco, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 9)
    Includes 27-page transcript of interview with Enrico Persico which took place in Rome on 8 April 1963.
  - Rayleigh, John William Strutt, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Reiche, Fritz, 1962; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 9)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in New York City on: 30 March 1962 (7 pages); 4 April 1962 (12 pages); and 9 May 1962 (17 pages).
  - Ritz, Walther, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Rosen, Nathan, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (Box 9)
    Letter to Thomas Kuhn